Sahil Ajmera

https://sahil-ajmera.github.io | sa7810@rit.edu | https://www.linkedin.com/in/sahil-ajmera-b6144092/ | https://github.com/Sahil-Ajmera | +1(646)571-9799

CAREER SUMMARY

Dedicated and versatile software engineer with one-year co-op experience in different domains handling different kinds of projects with skills in programming and building and maintaining software applications. Seeking an entry-level position as a Software Developer. Available - December 2019.

EDUCATION

Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester, New York

Expected December 2019

Master of Science in Computer Science

GPA: 3.96 / 4.0

Relevant Coursework: Algorithms, Data Structures, Introduction To Big Data, Foundations of Intelligent Systems, Introduction to Computing Security, Advanced Database Systems, Information Retrieval and Text Analytics, Codecademy-'Learn Angular JS 1.X'

Manipal Institute of Technology, Manipal, Karnataka, India

Earned 2017

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science

SKILLS

Certifications: Oracle Certified Professional JAVA SE6 Programmer, Microsoft Technical Associate for Cloud Fundamentals

Programming Languages: Python, Java, C#

Relational Database Management Systems: SQL, MySQL, SQL Server, Oracle 11g

Web Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, .NET, Materialize

Desktop Application Development: Qt

Orchestration Tools: Juju Charms, Ansible Playbooks

Source Control: Git

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux

EXPERIENCE

Lenovo Software Development Co-op – Data Center Group Morrisville, North Carolina

August 2018 - May 2019

- Added features to Lenovo's RHHI offering by leading efforts on instantiation, configuration and validation of platforms like CloudForms, ManageIO and Gitlab. (Presented at MWC-2019 and RH Summit 2019)
- Created a desktop application for ForkLift operators that gives information about the load they are carrying and the lane they are carrying that load to. (Presented at MWC – 2019 and Lenovo Accelerate 2019)
- Created 3 Rapid Access Demos (RADs) as a means of proof of technology allowing customers and partners with remote testing of Lenovo Data Center solutions.
- Technologies used Python, C#, Juju Charms, Qt, MQTT, RHVM, CloudForms, ManageIQ, Ansible, Materialize, .NET

American Institutes For Research

Washington, District of Columbia

May 2018 - August 2018

Software Engineer Intern • Integrated existing workflow of Item Card report generation into workflow of Custom Pdf report generation so that statistics of items can also be printed while making a Custom Pdf Report.

- Diagnosed bugs and implemented new features as per client requirements.
- Decreased the time that will take in later development operations by documenting existing code.
- Technologies Used: C#, .NET, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ajax, SQL, SQL Server

PROJECTS

Mobile App Review Classifier

June 2018 - August 2018

- Created 5 Naïve-Bayes classifiers to classify app reviews obtained from Google Play store as information giving, information seeking, bug report, feature request and displaying positive/negative/neutral sentiment.
- Created a web application that gives all the above information when an app review is input into the text field.
- Achieved F-measure values of 30%, 37%, 62.5%, 48.7%, 81.58% respectively for the 5 classifiers formed.
- Technologies Used: Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Flask

Gender Recognition: Technique using PCA and GA

January 2017 - April 2017

- Achieved a 6% accuracy improvement over traditional gender recognition technique on the FERET dataset.
- Technologies Used: Python, MATLAB, WEKA